今回はレストランなどでの注文にまつわる表現を練習します。
まず、注文するときの基本表現。
何々にします。
これを英語で言うと、
答えは、
I'll have.
I will have, or 短く, I'll have 〜。
以前も練習しましたね。
それを応用して、
例えば、最初は〜にします。
あるいは、〜だけにします。
など、今回表現できるようになりましょう。
And one more thing today,
our radio show will be in almost all English.
今日のレッスンはほぼオールイングリッシュで進みます。
You can do it!
Okay, it's time for your first try.
S-P-R-J
Now, I'll say something in Japanese and you express it in English within the time limit.
Before we do the first one, how do you say saisho ni in English?
Saisho ni is to start.
So, let's use to start to say this phrase.
最初に何か飲み物はいかがですか?
To start, would you...
軽い言ってみよう。
Go ahead.
Here's the next one.
最初はオレンジジュースにします。
どれくらいおなかがすいていますか?
それほどおなかはすいていません。
サラダだけにします。
OK, let's go to the next one.
First, how do you say ぜんさい?
The answer is appetizer.
Okay, use appetizer to say this.
前菜だけにします。
割とお腹が空いています。
Okay, let's go to the next sentence.
その前に料理の2,3品
How do you say that in English?
The answer is 2 or 3 dishes.
Okay, use 2 or 3 dishes to say this.
料理を2,3品注文してシェアしますか?
Shall we?
Go ahead.
OK, here's the next one.
すみません、注文をお願いします。
この料理にします。
その料理を食べてみるのがすごく楽しみです。
OK, time's up. How did you do? Did you try to say each one?
Now, Jenny and I will show you the sample answers and give you some advice.
So listen closely.
最初に何か飲み物はいかがですか?
To start, would you like something to drink?
最初はオレンジジュースにします。
To start, I'll have some orange juice.
So, we use the phrase to start and then 注文する定番表現.
I'll have そして飲み物の前によく酢酸も使いますね。
To start, I'll have some orange juice.
Here's the next one.
どれくらいお腹が空いていますか?
How hungry are you?
それほどお腹は空いていません。
I'm not that hungry.
サラダだけにします。
I'll just have a salad.
料理一品ですから、a salad。
Here's the next one.
前菜だけにします。
I'll just have an appetizer.
割とお腹が空いています。
I'm pretty hungry.
料理を二、三品注文してシェアしますか?
Shall we order two or three dishes and share?
Sumimasen, chumon wo onegai shimasu.
Excuse me, we'd like to order.
You wait for someone to come near your table, or you make eye contact, and then say this.
Alright, here's the next one.
Kono ryouri ni shimasu.
I'll have this dish.
Sometimes on a menu, the name of the dish is very difficult to pronounce,
even for native speakers like me.
And in that case, I point to the menu and say,
I'll have this dish.
Sono ryōri o tabete miru no ga sugo ku tanoshimi desu.
I'm so excited to try that dish.
To say tanoshimi, there are three phrases.
I'm looking forward to, I'm so excited to, or I can't wait to.
All are fine.
しかし、ものすごく楽しみ。
For that, instead of looking forward to, I suggest I'm so excited to, plus a verb.
I'm so excited to try that dish.
Okay. Did you understand today's phrases?
All right. Now it's your turn to try them one more time.
This is your chance to do a little better than before.
Okay, let's go.
最初に何か飲み物はいかがですか?
To start, would you like something to drink?
最初はオレンジジュースにします。
To start, I'll have some orange juice.
どれくらいお腹が空いていますか?
How hungry are you?
それほどお腹は空いていません。
I'm not that hungry.
サラダだけにします。
I'll just have a salad.
前菜だけにします。
I'll just have an appetizer.
割とお腹が空いています。
I'm pretty hungry.
料理を2、3品注文してシェアしますか?
Shall we order two or three dishes and share?
すみません。注文をお願いします。
Excuse me. We'd like to order.
この料理にします。
I'll have this dish.
Sono ryori wo tabete miru no ga sugoku tanoshimi desu.
I'm so excited to try that dish.
Alright, everyone. Time's up.
Well, how did you do? Those are some great phrases for ordering at a restaurant. You'll use those a lot when you travel.
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
Ekaewa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.